{"test_questions": [[{"question": "What about the stability of system in", "opta": "system is stable", "optb": "unstable", "optc": "stable at 0.4", "optd": "cant say", "ans": "A", "explanation": "ROC include the unit circle hence it is stable."}, {"question": "Which one most appropriate dynamic system?", "opta": "y(n) + y(n - 1) + y(n + 1)", "optb": "y(n) + y(n - 1)", "optc": "y(n) = x(n)", "optd": "y(n) +  y(n - 1) + y(n + 3) = 0", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Because present output of y(n) depend upon past y(n - 1) and future y(n + 1)."}, {"question": "An energy signal has G(f) = 10. Its energy density spectrum is", "opta": "10", "optb": "100", "optc": "50", "optd": "20", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Energy density spectrum = |G(f)|2 = |10|2 = 100."}, {"question": "Consider Pole zero diagram as shown, If two Poles are moved in opposite direction towards \u03c9 = p/2 and -p/2, the filter will be", "opta": "change to high pass filter", "optb": "change to Band Pass filter", "optc": "remains same", "optd": "change to LPF", "ans": "C", "explanation": "But still we will get the same response, zero are at same position."}, {"question": "In an ac circuit the fundamental component of current wave lags the corresponding voltage wave by 20\u00b0. The third harmonic component of current wave lags the corresponding voltage by an angle.", "opta": "less than 20\u00b0", "optb": "more than 20\u00b0", "optc": "equal to 20\u00b0", "optd": "equal to or more than 20\u00b0", "ans": "B", "explanation": "For third harmonic \u03b8 = tan-1 = ."}, {"question": "If  and A + B is", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Add elements individually."}, {"question": "A voltage V(t) is a Gaussian ergodic random process with a mean of zero and a variance of 4 volt2. If it is measured by a dc meter. The reading will be", "opta": "0", "optb": "4", "optc": "2", "optd": "2", "ans": "A", "explanation": "DC meter reads mean value."}, {"question": "A first order system will never be able to give a __________ response band stopband passall pass Choose the correct option", "opta": "1, 2, 3 true", "optb": "1 and 3 true, 2 false", "optc": "1, 2 are true 3 is false", "optd": "1, 2 are false, 3 is true", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Because to design band pass or band stop, transfer function of must be second order."}, {"question": "In the given figure the ratio T/d is the duty factor.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "B", "explanation": "."}, {"question": "If \u00a3[f(t)] = F(s), then \u00a3[f(t - T)] =", "opta": "est F(s)", "optb": "e-st F(s)", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "B", "explanation": "A linear system is one in which the relationship between input and output is linear. \n\nAll linear system possess the property of superposition i.e.,  if input u1 gives output y1 and input u2 gives output y2 then input u1 + u2 will give output y1 + y2. \n\nSuperposition implies homogencity i.e.,  if input u gives output y, then input ku gives output ky where k is a rational number. \n\nIn general a system is linear if a transformation T satisfies the relation\n\nT(au1 + \u03b2u2) = aT(u1) + \u03b2T(u2)\n\nwhere a and \u03b2 are constant."}, {"question": "The z-transform of a particular signal is given  whereThe system after implementation will be", "opta": "casual and stable", "optb": "non-casual and stable", "optc": "non-casual and unstable", "optd": "casual and unstable", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Include unity circle and exterior of circle hence x(z) will be stable, causal."}, {"question": "The system with given pole-zero diagram is", "opta": "casual", "optb": "non-casual", "optc": "both sided", "optd": "not-possible", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Because no.of zero is more than Pole, therefore when you find transfer function.\n\nNumerator power will higher than denominator, and such transfer functions is not realizable."}, {"question": "A pole zero pattern of a certain filter is shown in figure. This filter must be", "opta": "LPF", "optb": "BFP", "optc": "HPF", "optd": "APF", "ans": "D", "explanation": "In transfer function, no of zeros = no. of poles, hence it is all pass fliter."}, {"question": "If transfer function of a system is H(z) = 6 + z-1 + z-2 then system is", "opta": "minimun phase", "optb": "maximum phase", "optc": "mixed phase", "optd": "none", "ans": "A", "explanation": "H(z) = 6 + z-1 - z-2, solve it by considering H(z) = 0 z = 1/3, -1/2 in H(z) only numerator.\n\nHence z = 1/3, - 1/2 will be zero, and if zero lies inside the unit circle, system will be of minimum phase."}, {"question": "The period of the function cos  is", "opta": "", "optb": "8s", "optc": "4s", "optd": "", "ans": "B", "explanation": "."}, {"question": "Let x(t) and y(t) with F.T. x(f) and y(f) respectively be related as shown in figure Then y(f) is", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "-X(f/2)ej2pf", "optd": "-X(f/2)e- j2pf", "ans": "B", "explanation": "By applying time shifting and scaling property."}, {"question": "Which one is a linear system?", "opta": "y[n] = x[n] x x[n - 1]", "optb": "y[n] = x[n] + x[n - 10]", "optc": "y[n] = x2[n]", "optd": "(a) and (c)", "ans": "B", "explanation": "For linearity\n\ny1[n] = x1[n] + x2[n - 10] ...(1)\n\ny2 = x2[n] + x2[n - 10] ...(2)\n\ny1[n] = x1[n] + x2[n] + x2[n - 10] + x2[n - 10] ...(3)\n\nNow find y1[n] + y2[n]\n\nCorresponding to x1[n] + x2[n] \n\nIt is same as equation (3) hence linear.\n\nBut in part (c) y[n] = x2[n]\n\n&Rightarrow; y1[n] = x21[n], y2[n] = x22[n]&Rightarrow; y1[n] + y2[n] = x22[n]...3\n\nBut y1[n] + y2[n]\n\nCorresponing x1[n] + x2[n] is y1[n] + y2[n] = {x1[n] + x2[n]}2\n\n= x12[n] + x22[n] + 2x1[n] x2[n]....4\n\nEquations (3) and (4) are not same hence not linear."}, {"question": "Laplace transform of a pulse function of magnitude E and duration from t = 0 to t = a is", "opta": "E /  s", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "C", "explanation": "."}, {"question": "The continuous time system with impulse response h(t) = is stable, for n is even, when", "opta": "a = 0", "optb": "a > 0", "optc": "a < 0", "optd": "a \u2264 0", "ans": "C", "explanation": "For stable system exponential must be -ve so that a < 0."}, {"question": "If I (s)  , initial value of i(t) is", "opta": "5A", "optb": "12.5 A", "optc": "0.05 A", "optd": "1250 A", "ans": "A", "explanation": "."}, {"question": "If then for this to be true x(t) is", "opta": "exp (j2p f/t)", "optb": "exp (-j2p f/t)", "optc": "exp (j2p ft)", "optd": "exp (-j2p f/t)", "ans": "C", "explanation": "If  \n\n\n\n\n\n."}, {"question": "For the discrete time system of the given figure", "opta": "yk - 0.5 yk - 1 - 0.25 yk - 2 = uk", "optb": "yk + 0.5 yk - 1 - 0.25 yk - 2 = uk", "optc": "yk - 0.5 yk - 1 + 0.25 yk - 2 = uk", "optd": "yk + 0.5 yk - 1 + 0.25 yk - 2 = uk", "ans": "C", "explanation": "uk + 0.5 yk - 1 - 0.25 yk - 2 = yk."}, {"question": "The analog signal m(t) is given below m(t) = 4 cos 100 pt + 8 sin 200 pt + cos 300 pt, the Nyquist sampling rate will be", "opta": "1/100", "optb": "1/200", "optc": "1/300", "optd": "1/600", "ans": "C", "explanation": "m (t) = 4 cos 100 pt + 8 sin 200 pt + cos 300 pt\n\nNyquist sampling freq fs \u2264 2fm where fm is highest frequency component in given signal and highest fm in 3rd part\n\n2pfmt = 300 pt\n\nfm = 150 Hz\n\nfs = 2 x 150 p 300 Hz\n\n."}, {"question": "The ROC of sequence in the Z.T. of sequence x[n] = an \u222a [n] is", "opta": "z > a", "optb": "z < a", "optc": "|z| > a", "optd": "|z| < a", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The simplest method to find the ROC. Put denominator to greater than zero."}, {"question": "In Laplace transform, multiplication by e-at in time domain becomes", "opta": "translation by a in s domain", "optb": "translation by (-a) in s domain", "optc": "multiplication by e-as in s domain", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "\u00a3e-at f(t) = F(s + a)."}, {"question": "A function having frequency f is to be sampled. The sampling time T should be", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Sampling frequency must be more than 2f. Therefore ."}, {"question": "The final value theorem is", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "A", "explanation": "\u00a3f(t) = \n\n\u00a3-1F(s) = f(t)\n\n\u00a3[a f1(t) + bf2(t)] = aF1(s) + bF2(s)\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\nwhere \n\n\u00a3[f(t - T)] = e-sT F(s)\n\n\u00a3[e-at f(t)] = F(s + a)\n\nInitial value theorem \n\nFinal value theroem \n\nConvolution Integral \n\n\n\nwhere t is dummy variable for t."}, {"question": "If", "opta": "- 12", "optb": "12", "optc": "20", "optd": "- 20", "ans": "A", "explanation": "det.|A| = 3(8 - 12) = - 12."}, {"question": "Inverse Fourier transform of sgn (\u03c9) is", "opta": "", "optb": "1", "optc": "U(t)", "optd": "", "ans": "A", "explanation": "By duality Property."}, {"question": "If I (s)  , the final value of i(t) is", "opta": "5A", "optb": "12.5 A", "optc": "0.05 A", "optd": "1250 A", "ans": "B", "explanation": ""}, {"question": "A signal m(t) is multiplied by a sinusoidal waveform of frequency fc such thatv(t)=m(t) cos 2pfctIf Fourier transform of m(t) is M(f), Fourier transform of v(t) will be", "opta": "0.5 M(f + fc)", "optb": "0.5 M(f - fc)", "optc": "0.5 M(f + fc) + 0.5 M(f - fc)", "optd": "0.5 M(f - fc) + 0.5 M(f - fc)", "ans": "C", "explanation": "It is a modulation process. The resultant has (f + fc) and (f - fc) terms."}, {"question": "A voltage wave having 5% fifth harmonic content is applied to a series RC circuit. The percentage fifth harmonic content in the current wave will be", "opta": "5%", "optb": "more than 5%", "optc": "less than 5%", "optd": "equal or more than 5%", "ans": "B", "explanation": "IC = V(j\u03c9C)."}, {"question": "Assertion (A):  If , the initial value of i(t) is 5AReason (R): As per initial vaue theroem", "opta": "Both A and R are correct and R is correct explanation of A", "optb": "Both A and R are correct but R is not correct explanation of A", "optc": "A is true, R is false", "optd": "A is false, R is true", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Initial value theorem when applied to I(s) gives 5 A."}, {"question": "\u03b4(t) is a", "opta": "energy signal", "optb": "power signal", "optc": "neither energy nor power", "optd": "none", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Because Unit step is a Power signal. So By trignometric identifies d(t) also power.\n\n."}, {"question": "The analog signal given below is sampled by 600 samples per second for m(t) = 3 sin 500 pt + 2 sin 700 pt then folding frequency is", "opta": "500 Hz", "optb": "700 Hz", "optc": "300 Hz", "optd": "1400 Hz", "ans": "C", "explanation": "."}, {"question": "The signal defined by the equations f(t) = 0 for t < 0, f(t) = E for 0 \u2264 t \u2264 a and f(t) = 0 for t > a is", "opta": "a step function", "optb": "a pulse function", "optc": "a shifted step function originating at t = a", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "It is a pulse lasting for t = a."}, {"question": "Inverse Laplace transform of  is", "opta": "2 exp (- 2.5 t) cosh (0.5 t)", "optb": "exp (- 2 t) + exp (- 3 t)", "optc": "2 exp (- 2.5 t) sinh (0.5 t)", "optd": "2 exp (- 2.5 t) cos 0.5 t", "ans": "B", "explanation": "f(t) = e-2t + e-3t."}, {"question": "Two function g1(t) and g2(t) with correlation of 6 has average power of 4 and 5 respectively. The power of g1(t) + g2(t) is", "opta": "9", "optb": "21", "optc": "3", "optd": "15", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Power of two correlated signal is P = P1 + P2 +2R1, 2(t)."}, {"question": "A box has 4 white and 3 red balls. Two balls are taken out in succession. What is the probability that both are white?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The probability that first ball is white is  and the probability the second ball is white is . The probability that both are white is ."}, {"question": "Z transform is a non-linear operation.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Z transform is a linear operation."}, {"question": "A signal g(t) = A then g(t) is a", "opta": "energy signal", "optb": "power signal", "optc": "neither energy nor power signal", "optd": "insufficient data", "ans": "B", "explanation": "."}, {"question": "The Fourier series of an odd periodic function contains", "opta": "odd harmonics only", "optb": "even harmonics only", "optc": "cosine harmonics only", "optd": "sine harmonics only", "ans": "D", "explanation": "For an odd function f(- x) = - f(x) Hence, only sine terms."}, {"question": "If , the terms in f(t) will have", "opta": "e-t and e-2t", "optb": "et and e2t", "optc": "te-t and te-2t", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "(s + 1) term will give e-t  and (s + 2) term will give e-2t ."}, {"question": "An impulse function consist of", "opta": "pure dc", "optb": "pure a.c", "optc": "entire frequency range with constant phase", "optd": "infinite bandwidth with linear phase vaariations", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Because F.T. of \u03b4(t) = 1, 1 is a Constant function ranging from -\u221e to +\u221e."}, {"question": "As per time displacement theorem in Laplace transformation, displacement in the time domain by T becomes", "opta": "division by s in the s domain", "optb": "division by e-sT in the s domain", "optc": "multiplication by s in the s domain", "optd": "multiplication by e-sT in the s domain", "ans": "D", "explanation": "\u00a3f(t - T) = e-st F(s)."}, {"question": "Which one is a causal system?", "opta": "y(n) = 3x[n] - 2x[n - 1]", "optb": "y(n) = 3x[n] + 2x[n + 1]", "optc": "y(n) = 3x[n + 1] + 2x[n - 1]", "optd": "y(n) = 3x[n + 1] 2x[n - 1] + x[n]", "ans": "A", "explanation": "For causal output must depend upon Present and past not on future."}, {"question": "If , the coefficient of term e-t in f(t) will be", "opta": "1", "optb": "0", "optc": "0.5", "optd": "2/3", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Coefficient of e-t = ."}, {"question": "Double integration of a unit step function would lead to", "opta": "an impulse", "optb": "a parabola", "optc": "a ramp", "optd": "a doublet", "ans": "B", "explanation": "."}, {"question": "If f(t) = A d(t - a), F(s) is", "opta": "A e-as", "optb": "A eas", "optc": "A a e-as", "optd": "Aa eas", "ans": "A", "explanation": "It is an impulse having area A and originating at t = a."}, {"question": "If  is the Laplace transform of f(t) then f(0+) is", "opta": "0", "optb": "", "optc": "27", "optd": "\u221e", "ans": "C", "explanation": "."}]]}